Guide to the Jascha Heifetz Collection ARS.0046
Archive of Recorded Sound
- 12" Sound Discs, 78 rpm discs
  - Commercially Released Recordings, 78 and 33 rpm discs
    - Box 17: Victor/RCA Victor/Victrola, 78 rpm discs
      - Respighi, Ottorino, 1879-1936. Fontane di Roma, 1927 January 4; 2 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 17, Disc 724-725)
        Title on label: The fountains of Rome: The fountain of Valle Giulia at dawn -- The Triton fountain in the morning -- The fountain of Trevi at mid-day -- The Villa Medici fountain at sunset
        Performed by London Symphony Orchestra; Albert Coates, conductor
        Victrola: G 9126A-1, I 9126B-2; CR894-I[triangle], CR895-IA[triangle] (matrix nos., disc 724); J 9127A, G 9127B-1; CR896-II[triangle], CR897-IIA[triangle] (matrix nos., disc 725)
        Recorded in London, January 4, 1927
      - Honegger, Arthur, 1892-1955. Pacific 231, 1928?; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 17, Disc 726)
        Performed by the Continental Symphony Orchestra; Piero Coppola, conductor
        Victor: 9276-A, 9276-B; D2 45723-1, C 45724-1 (matrix); CTR-3389-I[triangle], CTR-3390-I[triangle] (additional matrix nos.)
        Recorded in Europe, November 16, 1927
      - Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Variationen über ein Thema von Haydn, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 17, Disc 727)
        Title on label: Variations on a theme by Haydn, op. 56a
        NB: Disc contains Variations 1-3; Variation 4 through the Finale is on Discs 728-729 in Box 18
        Performed by the London Symphony Orchestra; Pablo Casals, conductor
        Victrola: I 9287A-2-2, D 9287B-1-2 (matrix), CR1612-II[triangle], CR1613-IA[triangle] (additional matrix nos.)
    - Box 18: Victor/RCA Victior/Victrola, 78 rpm discs
      New York Philharmonic; Vronsky, Vitya; Philadelphia Orchestra; Toscanini, Arturo; London Symphony Orchestra; Voorhees, Donald; Casals, Pablo; Iturbi, Jose; Walton, William, 1902-1983; Babin, Victor; Suesse, Dana; Collingwood, Lawrance; Benoist, André; Sharpe, Cedric; Primrose, William; Bellezza, Vincenzo; Rubinstein, Artur; Ormandy, Eugene, 1899-1985; Victor Symphony Orchestra; Chaliapin, Fyodor Ivanovich; Victor Mixed Chorus; Stokowski, Leopold, 1882-1977; Lindbergh, Charles A. (Charles Augustus), 1902-1974; Newton, Ivor; Whiteman, Paul; Steimann, M; Bampton, Rose; Gigli, Beniamino; Goehr, Walter; Fiedler, Arthur; Pelletier, Wilfrid; Feuermann, Emanuel; Bay, Emanuel; Rupp, Franz; Kreisler, Fritz; Royal Opera House (London, England); Barbirolli, John, Sir; New Symphony Orchestra of London; Goossens, Eugene; Coates, Albert; Boston Pops Orchestra; Busch, Fritz; BBC Symphony Orchestra; London Philharmonic Orchestra
      - Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Variationen über ein Thema von Haydn, 2 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 18, Disc 728-729)
        Title information on label: Variations on a theme by Haydn, op. 56a
        NB: Discs contains Variation 4 through the Finale; Variations 1-3 are on Disc 727 in Box 17.
        Victrola: E 9288A-1-1, G 9288B-1-1 (matrix), CR1614-1[triangle], CR1615-1A[triangle] (additional matrix nos.); 9289A-1-1, A 9289B-1 (matrix), CR1616-1A[triangle], CR1617-1A (additional matrix nos.)
      - Borodin, Aleksandr Porfirʹevich, 1833-1887. Kni︠a︡zʹ Igorʹ. Polovet︠s︡kai︠a︡ pli︠a︡ska. Selections, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 18, Disc 730)
        Title on label: Prince Igor-ballet music
        Performed by Chorus and the London Symphony Orchestra; Albert Coates, conductor
        Victrola: F 9474A-1-1, D 9474B-1 (matrix); CR1554-1[triangle], CR1555-1A[triangle] (additional matrix nos.)
      - Bax, Arnold, 1883-1953. Tintagel -- Bax, Arnold, 1883-1953. Mediterranean; arr., 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 18, Disc 731-732)
        Performed by New Symphony Orchestra; Eugene Goossens, conductor
        Victrola: A 9787A-2, B 9787B-1A-1 (matrix), CR2017-2[triangle], CR2018-1A[triangle] (additional matrix nos.); B 9788A-A1, A 9788B-2 (matrix), CR2019-1A, CR2025-2[triangle] (additional matrix nos.)
      - Sibelius, Jean, 1865-1957. Saga -- Sibelius, Jean, 1865-1957. Kuolema. Valse triste, 2 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 18, Disc 733-734)
        Performed by [unidentified] Symphony Orchestra; Eugene Goossens, conductor
        Victrola: A 9925A-1A, A 9925B-2A-1 (matrix), Cc18794-1A[triangle], Cc18795-2A[triangle]; B 9926A-2A, A 9926B-1 (matrix), Cc18796-2[triangle],Cc18799-1[triangle]
      - Mussorgsky, Modest Petrovich, 1839-1881. Boris Godunov (Rimsky-Korsakov). Uzh kak na nebe solnt︠s︡u krasnomu slava, slava!, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 18, Disc 735)
        Performed by [unidentified] Symphony Orchestra with chorus; Albert Coates, conductor
        Victor: N 11485A-3, J 11485B-1 (matrix), Cc7064-3[triangle], Cc7066-1[triangle] (additional matrix nos.)
      - Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893. Lebedinoe ozero. Selections, 2 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 18, Disc 736-737)
        Title information on label: The swan lake-ballet suite
        Performed by the London Philharmonic Orchestra; John Barbirolli, conductor
        Victor: 2A 11666A-1-1, 2D 11666B-1 (matrix), 2B3545-1[square], 2B3546-1[square] (additional matrix nos.); 11667A XA1-1-3-2, 11667B XA1D-2 (matrix), 2B3548-1[square], 2B3547-2[square] (additional matrix nos.)
      - Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Till Eulenspiegels lustige Streiche, 2 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 18, Disc 738-739)
        Additional title information on label: Till Eulenspiegel’s merry pranks, op. 28
        Performed by the B.B.C. Symphony Orchestra; Fritz Busch, conductor
        Victor: 11724A D-2, 11724B 2-1 (matrix), 2B6811-2[square], 2B6812-1[square] (additional matrix nos.); C 11725A-1-2, W 11725B-2 (matrix), 2B6813-1[square], 2B6814-2A[square] (additional matrix nos.)
      - Ponchielli, Amilcare, 1834-1886. Gioconda. Danza delle ore, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 18, Disc 740)
        Title on label: Dance of the hours, Act 3, La gioconda
        Performed by the Boston “Pops” Orchestra; Arthur Fiedler, conductor
        Victor: 11833A-1, 11833B-1 (matrix)
      - Walton, William, 1902-1983. Façade (Suite no. 1), 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 18, Disc 741)
        Title on disc: Façade-suite
        Performed by London Philharmonic Orchestra; William Walton, conductor
        Victor: B 12034A-1A, C 12034B-2A (matrix), 2EA2907-1A[square], 2EA2908-2A[square] (additional matrix nos.)
      - Milhaud, Darius, 1892-1974. Scaramouche, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 18, Disc 742)
        Victor: C 12726A-2, C 12726B-1 (matrix)
      - Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Rosenkavalier (Opera). Ohne mich; arr., 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 18, Disc 743)
        Title on label: Rosenkavalier-waltz
        Victor: A 13150A-1, B 13150B-1 (matrix)
      - Busoni, Ferruccio, 1866-1924. Duettino concertante nach Mozart, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 18, Disc 744)
        Victor: C 13500A-3, C 13500B-2 (matrix)
      - Rossini, Gioacchino, 1792-1868. Italiana in Algeri. Sinfonia, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 18, Disc 745)
        Title on label: Italians in Algeria-Overture
        Performed by Philharmonic-Symphony Orchestra of New York; Arturo Toscanini, conductor
        Victor: C 14151A-1, C 14161B-1 (matrix)
      - Saint-Saëns, Camille, 1835-1921. Danse macabre (Symphonic poem), 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 18, Disc 746)
        Additional title information on label: Dance of death (Symphonic poem), op. 40
        Victor: 1416214162A-1, A 14162B-1 (matrix)
      - Mussorgsky, Modest Petrovich, 1839-1881. Boris Godunov (Rimsky-Korsakov). Chasy s kurantami -- Mussorgsky, Modest Petrovich, 1839-1881. Boris Godunov (Rimsky-Korsakov). Monolog Borisa, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 18, Disc 747)
        Titles on labels: I am suffocating (Clock scene), Act 2 -- I have attained the highest power (Monologue of Boris), Act 2
        Performed by Feodor Chaliapin, bass; unidentified orchestra; M. Steimann, conductor
        Victor: 14517A D-2, 14517B KA2-3 (matrix), 2B578-2[triangle], 2B577-3[triangle] (additional matrix nos.)
      - Mussorgsky, Modest Petrovich, 1839-1881. Boris Godunov (Rimsky-Korsakov). Chasy s kurantami -- Mussorgsky, Modest Petrovich, 1839-1881. Boris Godunov (Rimsky-Korsakov). Monolog Borisa, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 18, Disc 748)
        Victor: B 14517A-2, F 14517B (matrix), 2B578-2[triangle], 2B577-3[triangle] (additional matrix nos.)
      - Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912. Pièces de genre. Mélodie; arr. – Rachmaninoff, Sergei, 1873-1943. Aleko. Kavatina Aleko, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 18, Disc 749)
        Additional title information on label: Song of mourning [side A] – The moon is high in the sky (from the opera Aleko) [side B]
        Performed by Feodor Chaliapin, basso; Ivor Newton, piano; Cedric Sharpe, violoncello [side A]; unidentified orchestra; Lawrance Collingwood, conductor [side B]
        Victor: 14902A-1-1, 14902B-1 (matrix), 2B885-1[triangle]Cc18156-1[triangle] (additional matrix nos.)
      - Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Herz und Mund und Tat und Leben, BWV 147. Jesus bleibet meine Freude; arr. -- Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Sonaten und Partiten, violin, BWV 1001-1006. Partita, no. 3. Preludio; arr., 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 18, Disc 750)
        Additional title information on labels: Chorale-prelude-Jesu, joy of man’s desiring [side A] – Prelude in E major (from Third partita for solo violin) [side B]
        Performed by The Philadelphia Orchestra; Eugene Ormandy, conductor
        Victor: C 14973A-2, C 14973B-2 (matrix)
      - Mussorgsky, Modest Petrovich, 1839-1881. Boris Godunov (Rimsky-Korsakov). Proshchaĭ, moĭ syn! umirai︠u︡., 1928 July 4; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 18, Disc 751)
        Title information on labels: Boris Godounow-Prayer of Boris (Act 4) [side A] – Boris Godounow-Death of Boris (Act 4) [side B]
        Performed by Feodor Chaliapin; Royal Opera House, Covent Garden; Vincenzo Bellezza, conductor
        Victor: D 15177A-1, C 15177B-1 (matrix), CR2142-1[triangle], CR2143-1[triangle] (additional matrix nos.)
        “Recorded during actual performance at Royal Opera, Covent Garden, London, on July 4, 1928”
      - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Zauberflöte. Ouverture, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 18, Disc 752)
        Title on label: Magic flute-overture
        Performed by the B.B.C. Symphony Orchestra; Arturo Toscanini, conductor
        Victor: A 15190A-1-1, 15190B-1-1 (matrix), 2EA6654-1[square], 2EA6655-1[square] (additional matrix nos.)
      - Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893. Quartets, strings, no. 1, op. 11, D major. Andante cantabile; arr. -- Dvořák, Antonín, 1841-1904. Humoresques, piano, op. 101. No. 7; arr., 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 18, Disc 753)
        Performed by Fritz Kreisler, violin; Franz Rupp, piano
        Victor: 15217A 1-A-1, X2 15217B-1 (matrix), 2EA6095-1[square], 2EA6100-1[square] (additional matrix nos.)
      - Strauss, Johann, 1825-1899. An der schönen, blauen Donau; arr. – Strauss, Johann, 1825-1899. G'schichten aus dem Wienerwald; arr., 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 18, Disc 754)
        Title information on labels: Blue Danube waltz, op. 314 – Tales from the Vienna woods, op. 325
        Performed by The Philadelphia Orchestra; Leopold Stokowski, conductor
        Victor: X 15425A-1, A2 15425B-1 (matrix)
      - Bazzini, Antonio, 1818-1897. Ronde des lutins -- Wieniawski, Henri, 1835-1880. Polonaise brillante, no. 1; arr., 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 18, Disc 755)
        Additional title information on labels: Dance of the goblins, op. 25 [side A] – Polonaise brillante in D major, op. 4 [side B]
        Victor: B 15813A-1, A 15813B-2-1 (matrix); 2EA4895-1[square], 2EA4856-2[square] (matrix)
      - Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Ouverture zur Oper Leonore, no. 1, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 18, Disc 756)
        Title information on label: Leonore overture no. 1 in C major, op. 138
        Performed by the B. B. C. Symphony Orchestra; Arturo Toscanini, conductor
        Victor: A 15945A-2, A 15945B-2 (matrix), 2EA7969-2[square], 2EA7970-2[square] (additional matrix nos.)
      - Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849. Introduction et polonaise brillante, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 18, Disc 757)
        Performed by Emanuel Feuermann, violoncello; Franz Rupp, piano
        Victor: A 17610A C-5, 17610B-4 (matrix)
      - Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918. Prélude à l'après -midi d'un faune, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 18, Disc 758)
        Additional title on labels: Prelude to the afternoon of a faun
        Victor: 17700A KBC A1A-1A, 17700B-1A-3A3 (matrix)
      - McDonald, Harl, 1899-1955. Legend of the Arkansas traveler -- Nováček, Ottokar, 1866-1900. Perpetuum mobile, violin, orchestra, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 18, Disc 759)
        Victor: 18069A-1, 18069B-1A (matrix)
      - Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Aïda. Celeste Aïda -- Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Aïda. O patria mia, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 18, Disc 760)
        Additional title information on labels: Recitative and aria: Celeste Aida (Heavenly Aida) [side A] – Recitative and aria: O patria mia (My native land) [side B]
        Performed by Beniamino Gigli, tenor; Walter Goehr, conductor [side A]; Rose Bampton, soprano; Wilfred Pelletier, conductor [side B]; Victor Symphony Orchestra
        Victor: C 18221A-1, I 18221B-1 (matrix), 2EA5255-1[square] (additional matrix no. on Side A)
      - Songs of the past, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 18, Disc 761)
        [side A] Good-bye Dolly Gray; After the ball; Sweet Marie; Where did you get that hat; Say au revoir but not good-bye; Daisy Bell; A hot time in the old town. [side B] The sunshine of Paradise Alley; Two little girls in blue; She was bred in old Kentucky; Comrades; The picture that is turned toward the wall; Little Annie Rooney; Johnny get your gun
        Performed by the Victor Mixed Chorus; unidentified orchestra and conductor
        Victor: C 35825A-6. C 35825B-17 (matrix)
      - Colonel Charles A. Lindbergh’s address before the Press Club at Washington D.C., June 11, 1927 – Col. Lindbergh’s souvenir record, concluded, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 18, Disc 762)
        Colonel Charles A. Lindbergh, speaker
        Victor: D 35834A-1, D 35834B-2 (matrix)
      - Songs of Ireland – Songs of Scotland, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 18, Disc 763)
        [side A: Ireland] The harp that once thro’ Tara’s halls; The last rose of summer; Love’s young dream; The wearing of the green; Killarney; Come back to Erin – [side B: Scotland] Scots wha’ hae’; Blue bells of Scotland; Loch Lomond; Coming thro’ the rye; Here’s health to Bonnie Scotland; Annie Laurie; The Campbells are coming; Will ye no come back again; Auld lang syne
        Performed by Victor Mixed Chorus; unidentified orchestra; unidentified conductor
        Victor: 35878A-5-1, K 35878-5-2 (matrix)
      - Carmichael, Hoagy, 1899-1981. Star dust – Suesse, Dana, 1909-1987. Blue moonlight, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 18, Disc 764)
        Performed by Paul Whiteman and his Concert Orchestra; vocal refrain by The Kingsmen and John Hauser [side A]; Dana Suesse, piano [side B]
        Victor: D 36159A-2, A 36159B
      - Kreisler, Fritz, 1875-1962. Caprice viennois, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 18, Disc 765)
      - Achron, Joseph, 1886-1943. Hebrew melody, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 18, Disc 766)
        Victrola: 8X 74568-3-8 (matrix)
      - Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847. Gesänge, op. 34. Auf Flügeln des Gesanges, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 18, Disc 767)
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; André Benoist, piano
        Victrola: 108 74583-2-7 (matrix)
      - Halvorsen, Johan, 1864-1935. Passacaglia, violin, viola, G minor, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 18, Disc 768)
        Victor: A 11-8151A-2A-1, C 11-8151B-4 (matrix)
      - Albéniz, Isaac, 1860-1909. Navarra; arr. – Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Stücke, piano, op. 118. Ballade, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 18, Disc 769)
        Performed by Artur Rubinstein, piano
        Victor: 11-8622A-1B2A, 11-8622B-1B1F (matrix)
      - Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849. Polonaises, piano, op. 53, A♭ major, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 18, Disc 770)
        Title on label: Polonaise in A-flat, op. 53, no. 6
        Performed by José Iturbi, piano
        Victor: R 11-8848A-2A-2, Q 11-8848B-6A
      - Waxman, Franz, 1906-1967. Carmen fantasy, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 18, Disc 771)
        Additional title information on label: “Based on themes from Bizet’s opera, ‘Carmen’”
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; RCA Victor Orchestra; Donald Voorhees, conductor
        RCA Victor: 11-9422A 4 1E, 11-9422B 1E (matrix)
      - Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Ellens Gesang, D. 839; arr. -- Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918. Plus que lente, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 18, Disc 772)
        RCA Victor: 11-9571A 1E 1, 11-9571B 1E 2 (matrix)
      - Achron, Joseph, 1886-1943. Hebrew melody -- Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Sonatas, piano, D. 850, D major. Rondo; arr., 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 18, Disc 773)
        RCA Victor: 11-9572A 1E-1, 11-9572B 1E-1 (matrix)
      - Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849. Nocturnes, piano, op. 72, no. 1, E minor; arr. -- Sarasate, Pablo de, 1844-1908. Danzas españolas, op. 22. Romanza andaluza, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 18, Disc 774)
        RCA Victor: 11-9573A 1E-1, 11-9573B 1E-1 (matrix)
      - Kroll, William, 1901-1980. Banjo and fiddle -- Korngold, Erich Wolfgang, 1897-1957. Musik zu Shakespeare's Viel Lärmen um nichts. Gartenszene, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 18, Disc 775)
        Title information on Side B: Garden scene (from incidental music to Much ado about nothing)
        RCA Victor: 12-0430A 1E [star], 12-0430B [star] (matrix)
    - Box 19: RCA Victor/Victor/World's Greatest Music, 78 rpm discs
      - Rachmaninoff, Sergei, 1873-1943. Romansy, op. 34. Vocalise; arr. -- Ravel, Maurice, 1875-1937. Sonatina, piano. Mouvt. de menuet -- Tansman, Alexandre, 1897-1986. Pièces, violin, piano. Mouvement perpétuel, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 19, Disc 776)
        RCA Victor: 12-0765A 1E 3 (matrix), 12-0765B 1E 2 (matrix)
      - Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918. Prélude à l'après-midi d'un faune, 12" red plastic 78 rpm sound disc (Box 19, Disc 777)
        Additional title on disc: Prelude to the afternoon of a faun
        RCA Victor: 18-0042A 1 (matrix), 18-0042B 1 (matrix)
      - Kroll, William, 1901-1980. Banjo and fiddle -- Korngold, Erich Wolfgang, 1897-1957. Musik zu Shakespeare's Viel Lärmen um nichts. Gartenszene, 12" red plastic 78 rpm sound disc (Box 19, Disc 778)
        Title on Side B: Garden scene from Incidental music to Much ado about nothing
        RCA Victor: 18-0168A 1E (matrix), 18-0168B 1E (matrix)
      - Respighi, Ottorino, 1879-1936. Antiche arie e danze per liuto, no. 3. Arie di corte, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 19, Disc 779)
        Performed by The Philharmonic Symphony Society of New York; John Barbirolli, conductor
        RCA: B 018872 1 (matrix), C 018873 1 (matrix); CS 018872, CS 018873 (on labels)
      - Toscanini recording, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 19, Disc 780)
        Disc is missing from the collection.
      - Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849. Nocturnes, piano, op. 9. No. 3 -- Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849. Nocturnes, piano, op. 15. No. 1, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 19, Disc 781)
        Performed by Artur Rubinstein
        Victor: 14962A 1, 14962B 2 (matrix nos.); 2EA4827-1[square], 2EA4826-2[square]
      - Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Quartets, strings, no. 16, op. 135, F major. Vivace; arr. -- Paganini, Nicolò, 1782-1840. Moto perpetuo, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 19, Disc 782)
        Victor: 15547A 2 (matrix), A 15547B 2 (matrix); M 590-1, M 590-2 (additional nos. on labels)
      - Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849. Waltzes, piano, op. 70. No. 3 -- Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849. Waltzes, piano, B. 56, E minor, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 19, Disc 783)
        Performed by Alexander Brailowsky, piano
        Victor: 18389A 2 3 (matrix), 18389B 2A2 1 (matrix)
      - Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Fidelio (1806). Ouverture -- Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Geschöpfe des Prometheus. Ouverture, 2 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 19, Disc 784a-784b)
        Disc 784a: Victor: 11-9005A 1 (matrix), 11-9005B 1 (matrix) Disc 784b: Victor: 11-9006A 1 (matrix), 11-9006B 1 (matrix) Set no. on labels: SP 2
      - Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893. Souvenir d'un lieu cher. Mélodie, 1920; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 19, Disc 785)
        Performed by Leopold Auer, violin.
        Label bears two inscriptions signed by Auer: "To dear Jascha Heifetz" and "New York, June 7th 1920 To my musical children L. Auer"
        Privately issued disc.
        Victor Special Record: [matrix no. not visible]
      - World's greatest music, 1938; 3 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 19, Disc 791a, 791b, 791c)
        Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Symphonies, D. 759, B minor
        Unidentified performers
        Recorded in six parts on three discs; copyright 1938.
        World's Greatest Music: SR-1A-2, SR-1B-1, SR-2A-1, SR-2B-1A, SR-3A-1, SR-3B-1 (matrix)
    - Box 21: Library of Congress, folders
      Halpert, Herbert; Lomax, Alan; Seeger, Pete; Sturz, Elizabeth Lyttleton; Begley, Justis; Ward, Wade; Smoke, Herb; Steele, Pete; Strong, Luther; Claunch, Earnest; Barker, Horton; Lomax, John Avery; Lomax, Ruby T. (Ruby Terrill)
      - Recordings from the Archive of American Folk Song, 1937; 1939; 12" 33 rpm vinyl sound disc (Box 21, Disc 895)
        Titles on labels: [side A:] Fiddle Tunes: The last of Callahan -- The ways of the world -- Glory in the meeting-house; [side B:] Grub Springs -- The eighth of January -- Sally Goodin -- Cindy
        Performed by Luther Strong at Dalesburg, KY, 1937 [side A]; W.E. Claunch, with guitar, at Guntown, MS, 1939 [side B]
        Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory: AAFS 9 A, AAFS 9 B; LCSA-67, LC-24-2179 [matrix, stamped in disc]; B258, B259 [additional nos. etched in disc]
        Field recordings made by Alan and Elizabeth Lomax [side A]; Herbert Halpert [side B]
      - Recordings from the Archive of American Folk Song, 1938 -- 1941; 12" 33 rpm vinyl sound disc (Box 21, Disc 896)
        Titles on labels: [side A:] Five-string banjo tunes: Old Joe Clark -- Chilly winds -- Cripple Creek -- Coal Creek march; [side B:] John Henry -- The train
        Performed by Wade Ward; Herbert Smoke; Pete Steele; Wallace Swann and his Cherokee String Band; Chub Parham
        Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory: AAFS 10 A, AAFS 10 B; LCSA-59, LCSA-64 [matrix, stamped in disc]; B260, B261 [additional nos. etched in disc]
        Field recordings made by Peter Seeger, Alan Lomax, and Elizabeth Lomax in North Carolina, Ohio, and Virginia
      - Recordings from the Archive of American Folk Song, 1937; 12" 33 rpm vinyl sound disc (Box 21, Disc 897)
        Titles on labels: [side A:] The golden willow tree (part 1) -- [side B:] The golden willow tree (part 2) -- The rambling boy
        Performed by Justus Begley, vocalist/banjo
        Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory: AAFS 31 A, AAFS 31 B; WD3-MC-3537-1, WD3-MC-3538-1 [matrix, stamped in disc]; LCM 539, LCM 540 [additional nos. etched in disc]
        Field recordings made by Alan and Elizabeth Lomax in Hazard, Kentucky
      - Recordings from the Archive of American Folk Song, 1939; 12" 33 rpm vinyl sound disc (Box 21, Disc 898)
        Titles on labels: [side A:] The two sisters -- [side B:] Lord Thomas and fair Ellender